[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
=Remnants of Gold=
(Adapted from Gu Long's
"Flying Eagle over the Great Land")
(The main characters
in this drama are fictional)
=Episode 11=
General Ha.
The Officer is no match for him.
I am a seventh-rank imperial
Embroidered Uniform Guard officer.
Have the twelve guards of
Gan-Liang all rebelled?
Arrest this jerk!
General Ha!
Are you okay, Officer?
Should we capture Tie Futu first?
Ha Bingzhong!
What are you all afraid of?
What's there to fear?
Everyone, look!
Every last one of you, look!
General Ha.
You dare trample
an Embroidered Uniform Guard officer?
You're finished.
You...
General Ha.
If an imperial officer dies here
and the imperial court
holds us accountable,
what will the General do?
Die, you scoundrel!
Everyone, disperse.
Carry the body out.
Yes.
This is outrageous.
Stop.
Move aside!
Officer Pu, please don't
make things harder for us.
With all this fighting
on the drill ground,
can't the Commander-in-Chief
hear it from inside?
The Commander-in-Chief hasn't left
the rear courtyard for three months.
General Ha has given orders.
Trespassers will be executed.
Guerrilla Commander Ha Bingzhong.
Even if a scoundrel takes my life,
is he the one rebelling,
or have all of you rebelled?
Where is Ha Bingzhong?
Take the body away.
Everyone, return to your posts.
(Camel Bell Inn)
I'm here to see the Commander-in-Chief.
Please pass along a message.
I'm here to tell the General
where 300,000 taels of gold
are buried in the great desert.
(Shaanxi Branch
Regional Military Commission)
Do you have any water?
Could I have a cup?
I've come all this way
without finding a drop of water.
I'll wait there.
Tell the General
that my name is Zhang Luyao.
Drink up.
- Double.
- Single.
(Sancang Terrace)
What's this?
Drinking.
Another round?
Again.
Come on.
I refuse to believe this.
Fill it up.
Come on, keep going.
- Single.
- Double.
What would you like?
A cup of water.
Just water?
I'm out of money.
- Single.
- Double.
Lady,
water costs money here, too.
The water here isn't good.
Have some of ours.
It's on us.
You brought your own water?
Out here in the great desert,
who wouldn't bring their own water?
Our water
is the best.
Your name is Zhang Luyao?
How did you know?
I heard you talking
to the men from the Regional Military
Commission Yamen by the road.
My hearing
is also the best.
Thank you.
What's your name?
I'm Yan.
This is my man.
You're drinking the water we gave you.
Aren't you afraid it's poisoned?
I am immune to all poisons.
Didn't you know?
Now we do.
But there's no poison in this water.
It's from Mount Pingfeng.
Yan gave you
the last of it.
Thank you.
Why are you following me?
We're worried something else
might happen to you.
Now you're worried?
Where is Ha Bingzhong?
Right here.
Close the door.
I need to speak with Officer Pu.
Going somewhere?
With all that gold, silver, and jewelry,
you must be going far.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm staying right here,
and waiting for you.
You've got some nerve.
I joined the army
in the eighth year of Hongwu.
From Shaanxi to Gansu,
I followed the General
through more than
a dozen battles, large and small.
As for courage,
I've always had plenty.
More than enough.
I came from the Capital to Liangzhou.
My investigation led me all the way
to the Yamen.
Tie Futu
was right by your side.
Tie Futu is dead.
Officer Pu,
what case are you investigating?
You killed Tie Futu to silence him.
Silencing him
made things easier for everyone.
But you tried to have Tie Futu kill me.
The plan was
for Officer Pu
to be killed by a criminal,
and then for that criminal to be killed
by the warriors of this residence.
That would have closed the case.
Unfortunately, I survived.
And your warriors don't dare touch me.
So perhaps you can now tell me
what you really want.
What I really want?
How do we close this case?
What will it take
for you
to leave the Ganzhou Guard?
Interesting.
Very interesting.
Liangzhou has been interesting
since the day I arrived.
If you can kill me, you do.
If you can't,
you negotiate.
Is that it?
The great desert
is harsh and unforgiving.
People here speak and act
differently from those in the Capital.
They don't beat around the bush.
But I'm here
to see the Commander-in-Chief.
You
are only a guerrilla commander.
The Commander-in-Chief
isn't nearly as restrained.
Officer Pu,
you should leave yourself
a way out too, shouldn't you?
Talk to me first.
If we can't come to terms,
then you can see the Commander-in-Chief.
Can you make decisions
for the Commander-in-Chief?
Officer Pu,
now you've
finally said something sensible.
No one can make decisions
for the General.
But everyone
can make their own decisions.
Then what decision
did you make for yourself?
Enough talk.
When there's little gold,
it's just gold.
But when there's enough,
it can decide things for us.
It's almost dark.
Luyao, what are you waiting for?
I'm waiting for someone to take me
into the Yamen.
We can help you.
Thank you.
I don't need any help.
Didn't your whole family die?
We can kill Tie Futu.
It'd be easy.
How much do you know?
We want to know what you know.
For example,
where are those 300,000 taels of gold
hidden?
(Shaanxi Branch
Regional Military Commission)
How much is there?
I haven't counted carefully.
About
1,200 taels of gold.
And
870 taels of silver.
Is it all yours?
It all belongs to the General.
When there's enough gold,
it can decide things for us.
So is this
enough or not?
It's quite a fortune already.
How do you think
we should close the case?
What will make me
leave the Ganzhou Guard?
This
won't close the case.
And I won't leave, either.
Officer Pu,
there are probably
over 700 taels of gold here.
Take this gold back to the Capital,
and you'll have enough wealth
to last half a lifetime.
Do the 27 lives
of the Zhang family mean nothing?
The General commands thousands of troops
guarding the northern frontier.
The Zhang family
were merely commoners.
The lives of commoners still count.
That account can't be settled?
If we can't settle it,
I'll call in the warriors outside
and we'll settle it together.
Then tell me, Officer Pu,
how should we settle it?
What about my share?
You
get nothing.
Fine.
Gold,
1,200 taels.
Silver,
870 taels.
Officer Pu,
pack them up well.
I'll
have the men outside
prepare a fast horse
for your return to the Capital.
I still need a written record.
A record of what?
How much gold and silver there is,
whose gold and silver it is,
and why it's being given to me.
Officer Pu,
you must be joking.
The Commander-in-Chief of Gansu
holds great power and authority.
I'm only a lowly Banner Commander.
What if you accuse me
of wrongdoing later?
With the amount
and reason clearly written down,
I'll dare to enjoy my wealth
when I return to the Capital.
Officer Pu,
you don't trust me?
How could I trust
a pack of scoundrels?
Write it.
If you won't,
I'll have the warriors outside
come in and write it.
There's no ink or inkstone.
Bring the brush, ink, and inkstone.
Hurry.
May I sit here?
Go ahead.
Since you know Tie Futu,
why didn't you ask him
where the gold is?
You said the gold was at
the Regional Military Commission Yamen.
Only Tie Futu would believe that.
He didn't believe it, either.
But he didn't know where else to go,
so he had no choice but to come back
and settle things with his accomplices.
Tie Futu's accomplices?
Who?
The Commander-in-Chief of Gansu,
General Pingxi.
Do you have any more water?
So you're waiting here
for them to take you inside,
then you'll kill Tie Futu
and the Commander-in-Chief, too.
If you have any more water,
could I have some?
Luyao,
if something can't be done,
then let it go.
Life
doesn't have to be so hard.
There's a kind of bird in Shu
that spends
its whole life flying through the sky.
As long as it keeps flying,
it never knows hardship.
So you do know
where those 300,000 taels
of gold are, don't you?
Yes.
Don't you want it for yourself?
People like you
are the ones who suffer.
We don't suffer.
How pitiful.
What?
You look down on us?
You think you're so special?
I'll dictate. You write.
Officer Pu,
don't push this too far.
And what if I do?
You'll lose everything
and end up with nothing, right?
Start writing,
and we'll see if I've gone too far.
What do you expect me to write?
The Commander-in-Chief of Gansu
and Guerrilla Commander Ha Bingzhong,
in their search for gold
from the previous dynasty...
Write.
Write!
Poisoned 27 members of the Zhang family,
residents of Liangzhou
under their jurisdiction,
and plotted to murder Pu Ying
of the Embroidered Uniform Guard,
who was investigating the case.
After their crimes were exposed,
to escape punishment,
the Commander-in-Chief of Gansu
and Guerrilla Commander Ha Bingzhong
(Commander-in-Chief of Gansu)
offered 1,200 taels of gold
and 870 taels of silver
as a bribe.
Why did you stop writing?
I almost forgot.
I also have 100 taels of gold here.
You issued the Zhang
Escort Agency's escort contract.
The escort fee
is also illicit money.
So that makes 1,300 taels of gold
offered by the Commander-in-Chief
of Gansu
and Guerrilla Commander Ha Bingzhong,
plus 870 taels of silver.
Write.
Officer Pu,
I never thought
you were this kind of man.
Neither did I.
Is there really no room to settle this?
To tell you the truth,
there might have been.
Do you know why the poisoned victims
killed one another?
You know?
The poison you used
on the Zhang family poisoned me, too.
When the poison took hold,
you looked like an evil spirit to me,
and I looked the same to you.
Everyone thought
they saw evil spirits killing people,
so they all tried
to kill those evil spirits.
Then how did you survive?
At the Zhang Escort Agency,
I came back from the brink of death.
When I opened my eyes,
the evil spirits were gone.
Instead, I saw a woman
who looked like a divine being.
Zhang Luyao.
Can you see me?
It felt like a dream.
If not for the gold,
we never would have met
in this lifetime.
That's why
there's no room to settle this.
Understand?
That woman
who looked like a divine being.
I understand.
Of all the mistakes we made,
we never should've
let that Zhang lady come back.
So does she know
where those 300,000 taels
of gold are now?
If she wants to know,
she'll find out.
The General
should be waking up soon.
Since there's no room to settle this,
Officer Pu,
and you are an officer
sent by the imperial court,
I'll report this matter
to the General
and ask him to come see you.
But in this written account,
those first five characters,
"Commander-in-Chief of Gansu,"
I, Ha Bingzhong,
dare not write any further.
I'll wait right here.
(Commander-in-Chief of Gansu)
Why are there so many men?
Vice General Li
just arrived from Suzhou.
He heard that the officer
from the imperial court
was nearly assassinated
on the drill ground.
Where is Vice General Li?
On the drill ground.
He wants to see the General.
I don't know
if the General is awake yet.
General Ha.
Everything was going well.
Now we can't leave.
What case is the Embroidered Uniform
Guard officer investigating?
Why is Vice General Li here?
The Commander-in-Chief hasn't left
the inner courtyard for three months.
I came to check on him.
Why did you bring so many men?
They're part of Suzhou's defenses
and traveled here with me.
What's so special about her?
Yes.
I've never met anyone crazier than you.
You couldn't do it?
I've never been able to resist you.
Report!
General Ha.
There's a woman outside.
She says she wants
to see the Commander-in-Chief.
A woman?
She says her name is Zhang Luyao.
She wants to tell the General
where the 300,000 taels...
Shut your mouth.
General Ha.
Are you delivering medicine?
I'll go in with General Ha.
The General has given orders.
Trespassers will be executed.
What case
is the imperial court investigating?
The Commander-in-Chief
killed for plunder
and abused the law for personal gain.
Nonsense.
Where is
the Embroidered Uniform Guard officer?
In the accounting office.
Vice General Li,
you can ask him yourself.
Bring that woman in.
Take her to the drill ground?
Take her to see the General.
I'll wait for her in the front hall.
Yes.
That woman may enter.
As for everyone else,
trespassers will be executed.
What if Vice General Li tries to enter?
Execute him.
Yes.
The General requests your presence.
I should've killed her just now.
She won't make it out alive anyway.
You still can't bear to kill her.
Yes.
Make way!
Open the gate.
(May Divine Might Protect Us Forever)
Zhang Luyao.
Yes.
Speak.
About what?
The 300,000 taels of gold...
Where is it buried?
You are
the Commander-in-Chief?
Yes.
Do you have any water?
I'm very thirsty.
Wait here.
This is all for Officer Pu?
It's not a gift.
It's a bribe.
Why?
I'm waiting here
for the Commander-in-Chief.
When he comes, you'll know why.
The Commander-in-Chief hasn't left
the inner courtyard for three months.
He still has to come.
He killed civilians in Liangzhou,
27 members of the Zhang family.
The Zhang family?
There's a woman on the drill ground
named Zhang Luyao.
She wants to see the Commander-in-Chief.
(Preview of the Next Episode)
The General is dead.
The General is dead!
- General!
Zhang Luyao is dead.
Wusu Sea lies to the north.
Do you think the gold might be there?
My name is Tang Zheng.
=Remnants of Gold=